Jeffrey R. Peters Curriculum vitae

CONTACT INFORMATION Center for Control, Dynamical Systems

and Computation Office: +1-805-893-2801

Mechanical Engineering Department

Mobile: +1-805-680-5961

University of California, Santa Barbara

Mobile: +1-805-680-5961

E-mail: jrpeters@enginee

2217 Engineering II,

Santa Barbara, CA 93106 USA

E-mail: jrpeters@engineering.ucsb.edu Website: engineering.ucsb.edu/~irpeters/

RESEARCH INTERESTS Human supervisory control, human-centered systems, robotic coordination and motion planning, autonomous systems and vehicles, distributed systems and control, estimation and non-linear optimization, distributed algorithms and computation, and applied mathematics.

**EDUCATION** 

#### University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA

Ph.D., Mechanical Engineering, 2011-

- Dissertation Topic: Cooperative Robotics and Mixed Teams
- Adviser: Professor Francesco Bullo
- Area of Study: Control Engineering

M.A., Applied Mathematics, December 2015

• Area of Study: Real and Complex Analysis, Numerical Analysis

M.S., Mechanical Engineering, December 2013

- Thesis Topic: Camera Coordination for Smart Intruder Detection
- Adviser: Professor Francesco Bullo
- Area of Study: Control Engineering

#### University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, IL

B.S., Mechanical Engineering, May 2011 GPA: 3.97 (4.0 scale)

- Bronze Tablet Honors
- Minor in Mathematics

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA

Graduate Student Researcher

Summer 2011-Present

Advisor Francesco Bullo

# United Technologies Research Center, East Hartford, CT

Systems Department Consultant

**Summer 2014, Summer 2015** 

- Supervisors: Amit Surana, Luca Bertuccelli
- Designed supervisory control schemes
- · Analyzed eye-tracking data

#### John Deere Construction and Forestry Division, Davenport, IA

Quality Engineering Intern

Summer 2010

- Supervisors: Ellen Huntley, Amanda Freese
- Implemented new quality monitoring software

#### John Deere, Agriculture Division, Waterloo, IA

# Manufacturing Engineering Intern

Summer 2009

Fall 2015, Fall 2011

- Supervisor: Michael Walker
- Identified root causes of assembly issues
- Developed new automated oil system

# REFEREED JOURNAL **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] J. R. Peters and L. Bertuccelli. Robust Task Scheduling for Multi-Operator Supervisory Control Missions. AIAA Journal of Aerospace Information Systems, 2015. Submitted.
- [2] J. R. Peters, D. Borra, B. E. Paden, and F. Bullo. Sensor Network Localization on the Group of 3D Displacements. SIAM Journal on Control and Optimization, 2015. To Appear.
- [3] J. R. Peters, V. Srivastava, G.S. Taylor, A. Surana, M.P. Eckstein, and F. Bullo. Human Supervisory Control of Robotic Teams: Integrating Cognitive Modeling with Engineering Design. IEEE Control Systems Magazine, 2015.
- [4] F. Pasqualetti, F. Zanella, J.R. Peters, M. Spindler, R. Carili, and F. Bullo. Camera Network Coordination for Intruder Detection. IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology, 2013.

# REFEREED Conference **PUBLICATIONS**

[1] J.R. Peters and L. Bertuccelli. Robust Scheduling Strategies for Collaborative Human-UAV Missions. American Control Conference, 2016. Submitted.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

OTHER REFERED [1] J.R. Peters and R. Patel. Thinking Robotics: Teaching Robots to Make Decisions. http://www.teachengineering.org/. 2015.

#### Misc. **PUBLICATIONS**

- [1] J.R. Peters, L. Bertuccelli, and A. Surana. Eye-Tracking Metrics for Task-Based Supervisory Control. arXiv preprint, arXiv:1506.01976, 2015.
- [2] J.R. Peters. Camera Coordination for Intruder Detection in 1D Environments. MS Thesis, Mechanical Engineering Department, University of California at Santa Barbara, December 2014.

- REFEREE SERVICE IEEE Transactions on Human-Machine Systems
  - IEEE Transactions on Control Systems Technology

#### STUDENT ADVISING

#### **Heather Vermilyea**

High school student at Dos Pueblos High School, Goleta, CA. Revisions and preparation for School for Scientific Thought class entitled "Thinking Robotics: Teaching Robots to Make Decisions" (see "Outreach"). June 2013-October 2013.

#### **Ariana Del Toro**

Undergraduate student in Mechanical Engineering, San Francisco University, RISE (Research Internships in Science and Engineering) Intern. Robotic Coverage Control: Theory and Implementation. June 2013-August 2013.

#### **TEACHING EXPERIENCE**

#### University of California, Santa Barbara, Santa Barbara, CA

#### **Teaching Assistant**

ME 104: Mechatronics.

Instructor: Brad Paden

Spring 2014

ME 16: Dynamics.

Instructor: Otger Campas

#### University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, IL

Grader

TAM 210: Statics Spring 2011

• Instructor: Richard Keane

### **Engineering Learning Assistant**

Eng 100: Intro to Engineering

Fall 2010

 Responsible for two 1 hour lectures per week to freshman engineering students and acting as a mentor to them. Students learned about various resources that were available to them, as well as about professional skills such as resume writing, job interview tips, etc.

### OUTREACH School for Scientific Thought

Winter and Fall 2013

- Taught a class to high school students entitled "Thinking Robotic: Teaching Robots
  to Make Decisions" in which students build a small robot and learn to program it to
  perform tasks such as simple navigation and object detection.
- Curriculum written for this class is published on www.teachengineering.org

#### Undergraduati Research

#### UNDERGRADUATE University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, IL

Effect of Controllers on Bistability in Atomic Force Microscopes

Fall 2010-Spring 2011

• Advisor: Srinivasa Salapaka.

Absorption of Solar Cells Containing InAS/GaAs Quantum Dots Based on Intermediate Band Placement

Spring 2010

Advisor: Harley Johnson.

# PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

Institute for Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE), Member, 2011-present

• IEEE Control Systems Society (2011-present)

# AWARDS AND DISTINCTIONS

University of California, Santa Barbara

Center for Control, Dynamical Systems, and Computation Outstanding Scholar Fellowship. 2011

#### University of Illinois

- Engineer in Training (EIT), 2011
- Bronze Tablet Distinction for Graduation with Highest Honors, 2011
- Earl and Althea Smith Scholorship, 2010
- Pi Tau Sigma Initiate Award, 2008
- Dean's List, 7 Semesters from 2007-2011

#### OTHER SKILLS

Instrumentation, Control, Data Acquisition, Test, and Measurement:

- Simulink,
- LabVIEW

### Computer Programming:

• Matlab, Python, C++

# Numerical Analysis:

MATLAB

#### **EXPERTISE**

#### Mathematics:

Applied Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Real Analysis, Topology, Differential Geometry, Graph Theory.

#### Control Theory and Engineering:

 Human supervisory control, Robotic coordination, Linear and Nonlinear Systems Theory, Feedback, Distributed Algorithms.

### Communications and Signal Processing:

• Probability, Random Variables, Estimation and Filtering

#### Computer Science and Engineering:

Convex and Nonconvex Optimization, Optimization on Manifolds, Numerical Algorithms for ODEs and PDEs

# Psychology and Human Factors:

Human-centered systems, Accumulator models for perceptual decision making, Exogenous factors

REFERENCES AVAILABLE TO CONTACT Available upon request.